

Lysanne Pinto

Technical writer and instructional designer with ~5 years of experience in software organizations. Proficient in planning, designing, developing, and managing product documentation and learning experiences centered on users and their goals.

Bilingual - fluent in English and French.

Skills

- Information architecture
- Content strategy
- Instructional design
- UI/UX writing
- Needs analysis

Content

- User guides
- Quick references
- Release notes
- UI text
- Embedded help
- API documentation
- Training courses
- Online and print
- Wikis

Tools

- MadCap Flare, RoboHelp, FrameMaker
- Jira, Confluence
- Crucible, Bitbucket
- Git, GitHub, Subversion
- MS Office, Project, Visio
- Camtasia, Snagit
- HTML, CSS, XML, JSON
- Swagger
- DITA

Education

Technical Writer — Post-graduate certificate program

Dean's Honours List

Algonquin College, Ottawa ON | 2015 - 2016

English with Minor in Philosophy — B.A honours program

Carleton University, Ottawa ON | 2010 - 2014

Experience

Snow Software — Technical writer

AUGUST 2019 - PRESENT

- Creating user guides, context-sensitive help, and release notes for hybrid cloud management software.
- Establishing technical writing best practices, and documentation styles and standards.
- Auditing content to identify gaps and providing recommendations on content strategy.
- Developing guidelines for UI text and embedded help.
- Researching API documentation and docs-as-code solutions.

IFS - Technical writer

SEPTEMBER 2018 - AUGUST 2019

- Planned and developed user guides for aviation maintenance software.
- Owned and curated the product release notes.
- Collaborated with other writers to establish writing styles and standards, and content templates.
- Wrote user stories and created story maps.
- Demonstrated new product features to customers and collected feedback.

Kinaxis - Content developer

MAY 2016 - SEPTEMBER 2018

- Planned, developed, and maintained content for user guides, context-sensitive help, embedded help, and role-based training courses for supply-chain management software.
- Ensured web content accessibility guidelines were maintained.
- Developed questions for certification exams.
- Created an applications guide using a script to single-source the in-product help to promote effective content reuse.